[music]
>> CUT. CUT. CUT. CUT. WHAT THE [__] ARE
YOU DOING?
>> [snorts]
>> THE WHOLE TRUTH DONUTS. Temptation baked
in. Willpower sold separately.
>> Everything you just saw started out as
one image of a donut. All the prompts,
characters, and locations were created
by me going back and forth with Claude
until I was satisfied and then
generating the videos in C Dance 2.5.
And in this video, I'm going to show you
that entire conversation and how I go
from ideas
>> [music]
>> to prompts to assets and then to videos,
including the failures, the location I
had to change on the fly, and the one
thing that fixes four broken generations
into a finished commercial. Welcome back
to our channel, and if you're new here,
hi. My name is Thomas, and I make videos
about AI and product photography. So, if
that's something you're into, consider
subscribing. In my previous video, I
created a cinematic coffee commercial
using C Dance 2.5, and so many of you
asked me, "How do I come up with the
prompts and the ideas to create these
commercials?" So, in this video, we're
going to take a look at that. The whole
idea of this video is to take you along
the journey when we go from a simple
product reference image, then turning
that idea into something that C Dance
2.5 could generate, and then creating
all the assets needed for that idea, and
then finally, generating the video and
putting it all together in post. And at
the end, I'm going to break down exactly
how much this whole process cost me down
to the credit. Today, I'm working inside
of Hicksfield, and if you want to follow
along for yourself, there's going to be
a link in the description below to a
project with all the assets and all the
prompts, so you can take a look at the
individual creations and which prompts
were used to create them. Thank you to
Hicksfield for sponsoring the video, but
now let's get into the workflow. Phase
one is probably the most important phase
where most people probably skip a lot of
steps and then when they start
generating, they don't have a solid
ground to stand on which then results in
bad generations. So, the first thing I
did is I uploaded the images of my
donuts and the single donut that I had
created from that and then started going
back and forth with Claude to create the
idea. So, this is the brief I gave it
and I want you to notice how much of the
details are still missing from this
initial brief. So, in here I wanted an
epic montage of the donut being made
with kind of speed ramp transitions and
effects and also I specified Laowa Probe
Lens macro shots. Now, if you don't know
what that is, Laowa Probe Lens is a long
weird lens which gives these unique
perspectives and it's usually used in
product commercials. Therefore, the
twist I wanted it to be a film crew
member grabbing the donut at the end and
then interrupting the filming of the
commercial itself. And in this idea,
there's two good things to think about
for the edit. There's this beautiful
montage that's kind of expected from a
product commercial, then with an
unexpected twist towards the end when
the crew member interrupts the
commercial. So, it's kind of similar to
the coffee one where it's a beautiful
montage and then we get interrupted by
the queue that's actually waiting for
the coffee to be served. And that's
called a pattern interrupt or a pattern
switch because we're going from
something beautiful and fast to
something slow and different and that's
always good to keep the attention or the
interest of the viewer. And this is the
first suggestion that came back from
Claude and as you can see, there's so
many cuts and we might have made a small
flaw because I never mentioned that
we're going to create it with CeeDance
2.5. But from the twist section, I
actually liked some of what the Claude
suggested, so I kept some of it and
answered like this. From my experience,
you want to give CeeDance 2.5 a maximum
of 12 to 15 cuts for a 30-second long
commercial in order for it to be able to
focus on each cut individually. And here
we have the rewritten second version
with our changes from Claude and now we
can really see that we have fewer shots
that is perfect for C Dance 2.5 cuz now
we can focus on the individual shots
better. I felt that there was one
important thing missing and at this
stage I lost about 20 to 25 minutes of
my life just going back and forth trying
to nail down that tagline at the end.
First, I really didn't know what I
wanted it to be and Claude kept
suggesting and suggesting because I
asked for 10 variations after 10
variations after 10 variations, but none
of them really felt right until I got
this line, "Temptation baked in." I
really liked the sound of that, so I
asked Claude to spin on that idea a
little bit more. And then after one more
round of variations, we finally got
"Temptation baked in, willpower sold
separately." But this is the thing I
want you to take away from the first
phase, the struggle and the time spent
on concepting and ideation because it
builds the ground for your whole
commercial after that. Everything after
this, the characters, the locations, and
the generations build on this ground
that you had set in the idea phase. And
it's a lot cheaper to argue with Claude
about the tagline for 25 minutes instead
of trying to fixing it by generating the
wrong commercial in the generation
phase, which brings us to phase two,
creating the assets. So here I open
Higgs Field on desktop, click Cinema
Studio, and start a new project. And I
like to do it this way because now I
have a project where I have a good
overview of all the assets that we're
going to create during the process. And
all the image and video tools are
available in Cinema Studio, so this way
you don't have to jump between tabs
either.
Okay, quick pause in the action from
future Thomas because literally while
I'm editing this video, Higgs Field
released C Dance 2.5 in 1080p
resolution, which is insane. And I'm
going to make a video on it next week,
so subscribe for that. But they also run
a promo where new users get five free
generations, so check it out from the
link below. Now, back to the video. So
we started by generating the character
reference sheets prompts with Claude.
And first, I forgot to attach the style
I always want for the prompts. And here,
I've seen online people doing this super
complicated character sheets with 10
different angles of the character and a
bunch of text and everything, but I
would recommend to keep it as simple as
possible. I usually use a close-up of
the face and then a front and back
full-body view of the character. And for
the image model, I always use Higgs
Field Soul Cinema because it's super
cheap to generate and I actually think
it gives the best cinematic characters
out there. And this step is super
important because the quality of your
output is always based on the quality of
your input. So, if your character
doesn't look realistic in your character
reference sheet, it's not going to look
realistic in the video generation. And
the first generation of the director
character sheet was completely wrong. He
looks like something out of a horror
movie. But, the one of the crew member
was actually really nice on the first
try. I just didn't like the scar on his
face, so I ran one edit to remove the
scar, but also remove the face from the
full-body front view. Now, if you
haven't seen my videos before, I always
do this that I remove the face from the
full-body front view just to remove any
confusion for C Dance of which face to
use when generating the video. I also
generated an image of some random crew
members to be added to the set when we
break the illusion. And you can go and
check for yourself from project I
published how many iterations I do for
the characters and also the locations.
And the look and feel of the locations
might be even more important than the
look of the characters because the
location is going to lock in the whole
look and color grade and everything how
the commercial actually feels. [music]
And you're going to see just in a little
bit why the locations that you use are
super important for how your generations
turn out. And the best part about this
stage is that you can take the results
you get from the character reference
sheets and the locations and send them
back to Claude and then just explain
what you want to change or what you want
to keep and Claude will do another
prompt looking at the image and then
adjusting it so it gets closer to your
vision. And I do this a bunch. I take
the image, send it back to Claude,
explain what I want to change, and then
Claude adjusts the prompt for me. When
we have the assets locked, I save them
as elements inside of Cinema Studio. I
then take a screenshot of the naming of
those elements and jump back into
Claude. And for this next part, you're
going to need the free Shotlist Director
skill that you can download from the
link below. And shortly, what it does,
it will use the assets that we created
and create a prompt with style,
characters, scenes, and then a timeline
with all the individual shots of the
commercial. And I believe this skill was
developed for the old version of C Dance
that was able to generate 15-second-long
commercials. So, make sure to mention
that you're using C Dance 2.5 and that
you want to generate a 30-second-long
commercial with all the cuts in one
prompt. And this is the first prompt I
got back from Claude. Always read
through the prompts carefully. I'm going
to explain why in just a second. Let's
take a look at the result.
>> CUT! CUT! CUT! CUT! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> THE WHOLE TRUTH DONUTS. Temptation baked
in. Willpower sold separately.
>> So, there was a lot of good in this
generation, but also a lot of bad. For
example, the most important thing that
we forgot was to mention the chef's
hands performing the actions in the
kitchen montage. So, we had a bunch of
shots where actions are happening and
stuff is moving, but no hands in the
picture. I also didn't like the beat
with the director coming in because
we're seeing him from behind and the
crew is randomly placed in the kitchen.
But then again, the ending sequence with
the guy looking at him, shrugging his
shoulders, and then the hero ending card
was perfect. [music] But now, instead of
trying to fix and regenerate the exact
same commercial with the exact same
shots, what we can do is ask for a
different type of montage with different
type of shots, so we get more variety in
the shot type that we have. And at the
same time, we can regenerate another
version of the section with the director
to be something closer to what I had in
my mind. So, this way we have a
completely unique second version of the
commercial, which will then give us more
variety when we cut everything together
in post. So, this was the prompt we used
for the second generation, and we got
this result.
>> [music]
>> CUT! CUT! CUT! CUT! WHAT THE [__] ARE
YOU DOING?
>> THE WHOLE TRUTH DONUTS. Temptation baked
in. Willpower sold separately.
>> All right. So, now we have a lot of
different shots for the montage that
turned out really good. But the section
with the director still failed, and I
think we have to approach that in a
different way to make it really work. I
feel that we need to start the
commercial on the chef to really make
the montage work. So, I went back to
Claude and asked for another version of
the montage starting with close-ups of
the chef herself.
>> CUT! CUT! CUT! CUT! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> THE WHOLE TRUTH DONUTS. Temptation baked
in. Willpower sold differently.
>> And no, we definitely had all the shots
we needed for the montage, but the
director shot still failed, so I had to
take a different approach. I took our
original location image with the film
set at the counter and used the Cinema
Studio edit feature to turn it around.
Because now with the viewpoint from the
counter looking at the camera, we can
generate the scene I actually want. The
director jumping out of his and
screaming at the crew member. I then
took this element, went back to Claude
and asked it for an edited version of
the ending part of the prompt only with
the donut being placed, the director
screaming, and then the close-up of the
guy eating the donut. So for this one,
we only needed a 12-second generation
and we got it on the first try.
>> CUT! GREAT! CUT! CUT! WHAT THE [__] ARE
YOU DOING?
>> YOU MIGHT HAVE NOTICED already looking
at this generation that Cines 2.5
sometimes adds music into the generation
even though we always ask for no music.
This seems to be a bug at least for
longer generations. Sometimes during the
generation, there will always be a
section that has some type of music in
it, which I'm not so fond of. But not to
worry, we can at least kind of avoid
this by cheating a little bit in post.
So this is what the final timeline looks
like. I brought in the four clips that
we generated and cut out the best parts
that I wanted to keep for the final
commercial. I then brought in the
soundtrack I wanted to use and here I
usually use real music because I just
think it's so much better than AI
generated music. And a bonus trick, when
you have a moment where everything goes
silent like in this commercial, you can
take the best part of the music track
and then cut out the ending section of
the song and have it fade back in at the
ending of the commercial, which will
again make it feel so much more
professional. And because our music
track is so much more dominant, it's
going to play over the small background
music that Seed AI 2.5 added to the
generations. But if you have problems
with this, you can always bring down the
volume of the music so that the Seed AI
generated music doesn't bleed into the
real commercial. But this of course also
gets rid of the sound effects from the
clips, so you might have to add those in
manually later. Then I just added a few
speed ramps to some of the clips and a
zoom effect at the end. And we got a
result that looks like this.
>> [music]
[music]
>> CUT! QUICK! CUT! CUT! WHAT THE [__] ARE
YOU DOING?
>> [snorts]
>> THE WHOLE TRUTH DONUTS. Temptation baked
in. Willpower sold separately.
>> I said that I was going to give you the
total credits spent of the whole
project. And in total we generated four
video clips with Seed AI 2.5, one
12-second long and three 30-second long
clips, which comes to 663
credits. On the image side, we created
224 assets in total, but most of the
images were created with Higgsfield
Cinema Soul and cinematic locations,
which are super cheap to use. So the
total spend was something around 100 to
200 credits. So that puts us on a
project total of under 1,000 Higgsfield
credits, which is pretty good for this
quality of a commercial in my opinion.
And that brings us to the one thing you
should take with you from this video is
that the hard part isn't the generation
anymore with Seed AI 2.5. The hard part
is what happens before you generate. The
ideas, the concepts, the characters, the
locations. Focus on those before you
start generating and you will generate
so much better results. But, if you
haven't seen my previous video I want
some coffee for your donuts, you can
check out this video right here. Make
sure to check out the school community
if you want to learn more about product
ads and product photography with AI.
But, other than that, I'll see you in
the next one.